beforetheflood.com 2019-12-23

# Before the Flood - Privacy

**One Earth, a project of Rockefeller Philanthropy Advisors** , the sponsoring organization of beforetheflood.com website ("us", "we", or "our"), is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy explains how we treat that information -- like your name, contact information, and issues that are important to you – and to show you all the ways we work hard to keep it safe and private. We encourage you to take the time to read it. Below is a list of commonly asked questions.

**What type of information do we collect information from you?  
**The personal information we collect, store and use about you might include:

• Your name and contact details (including postal address, email address and telephone number);

• Your responses to optional polls, petitions or other forms that we may invite you to complete;

• Details of any donations you make, including the amount, currency, and method of payment. We do not store your credit card information or banking details -- that’s done through third payment processors, including Classy and WePay;

• Your social media account IDs and information shared with us via your social media accounts;

• Data relating to whether you open our emails, click our email links, sign or share petitions, and if the people you shared with sign our petitions;

• Images, photographs, or video you upload to the site;

• Other information you voluntarily submit in a form on the site or that you share when you contact us.

We also collect from all visitors:

• Technical information about your use of the website, browser type and version, and operating system;

• Your IP Address;

• Cookies (see below). 

Data protection laws recognize certain categories of personal information as sensitive and therefore requiring greater protection. We do not usually collect sensitive data about you unless there is a clear and valid reason for doing so and applicable data protection laws allow us to.

**Cookie Policy  
**“Cookies” are small pieces of information sent by an organization to your computer and stored on your hard drive to allow that website to recognize you when you visit. For example, we can use cookies to store your country preference. This helps us to deliver a more personalized service when you browse our website and improves our services.

European and other national data privacy regulations state that we can store cookies on your device if they are strictly necessary for the operation of this site, enabling basic functions like page navigation and access to secure areas of the website. For all other types of cookies, we need your permission.

This site uses different types of cookies, pixel tags, and other technologies. Some cookies are placed by third party services that appear on our pages. 

**How and why is your information used?  
**We may use your information for a number of different purposes, which may include:

• Sending you communications which you have requested and that may be of interest to you. These may include newsletters, project updates, or invitations to take further action;

• Highlighting your participation in a campaign by displaying your first name and first initial of your last name, country, and the campaign you took action online or in printed or PDF materials;

• Contacting you to thank you for signing, donating or verifying your identity via email, phone/text or direct mail;

• Keeping a record of your relationship with us;

• Conducting analysis to better understand how we can improve our services, products or information;

• Notifying you of changes to our services.

**How long is your information kept for?  
**We keep your information for no longer than is necessary for the purposes it was collected for. The length of time we retain your personal information is determined by operational and legal considerations. For example, we are legally required to hold some types of information to fulfill our statutory and regulatory obligations. We review these retention periods on a regular basis. If you request that we stop sending you updates and other communications or delete your information, we will honor your request and keep the minimum amount of information possible to prevent fraud and to help ensure that you are not contacted again.

**How can I unsubscribe?  
**If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from an email list, you may do so by clicking on the “Unsubscribe” link included at the bottom of every campaign email that you receive from us.

**Who has access to your information?  
**We do not rent or sell your personal information.

When you sign a petition, the target of the campaign is sent a final list including the redacted name, of the individual, country, and any comments of everyone who signed. Where the target is a government body or official that requires petition signers to be constituents, we may also provide your postal code and full address if collected.

We may also pass your information to our third-party service providers, suppliers, agents, subcontractors, and other associated organizations for the purposes of completing tasks and providing services to you on our behalf (for example, to process donations and send you mailings). However, when we use these third parties, we disclose only the personal information that is necessary to deliver the services, and we have a contract in place that requires them to keep your information secure and prevents them from using it for their own direct marketing purposes.

Please be reassured that we will not release your information to third parties to use for their own direct marketing purposes, unless you have requested us to do so, or we are required to do so by law, for example, by a court order or for the purposes of prevention of fraud or other crime.

**How do we keep your information safe?  
**We use standard industry practices, such as firewalls and encryption, to safeguard your personally identifiable information against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure, misuse, or destruction. All donations, including the transmission of payment details and other personal information, are handled over secure, encrypted connections. 

As part of the services offered to you through this website, the information which you provide to us may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). By way of example, this may happen if any of our servers are from time to time located in a country outside of the EEA. You should be aware that these countries may not have similar data protection laws to the GDPR. By submitting your personal data, you’re agreeing to this transfer, storing or processing. If we transfer your information outside of the EEA in this way, we will take steps to ensure that appropriate security measures are taken with the aim of ensuring that your privacy rights continue to be protected as outlined in this policy.

If you use our services while you are outside the EEA, your information may be transferred outside the EEA in order to provide you with those services. We undertake regular reviews of who has access to information that we hold to ensure that your information is only accessible by appropriately trained staff, volunteers and contractors.

**How can you update and correct your personal information?  
**You can review and update your personal information at any time by contacting us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) For users in Europe and other countries that adhere to GDPR standards, you also have the right to:

• **Restrict** or **Erase** : You can ask us to limit our use of your information or ask us to delete some or all of your personal information from our records if there is no compelling reason for us to hold on to it. In some cases, we will anonymize that information, rather than delete it, if allowable.

• **Object** : You can object, on legitimate grounds, to the processing of your personal information, including direct marketing and profiling. And you have a right to have inaccurate personal information corrected if requested.

• **Access** or **Take** your data: You can ask us to confirm whether we are processing your personal information. You can also make a reasonable request for a copy of that information or to have it transferred to another data controller to the extent possible.

• **Complain** : You can complain to the UK Information Commissioner’s Office or your country’s data protection authority.

Exceptions apply to a number of these rights, and not all rights will be applicable in all circumstances. For more details, we recommend you consult the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) guidance published by the [Irish Data Privacy Commission](http://gdprandyou.ie/).

**What is the lawful basis for processing your information?  
**Data protection law requires us to rely on one or more lawful bases to process your personal information. Lawful bases include consent (where you have given consent) and our legitimate interest in operating, managing and promoting our organization, maintaining our relationship with you, and protecting the website, provided that such processing shall not outweigh your rights and freedoms. Where we rely on your consent to process personal data, you have the right to withdraw or decline your consent at any time. This includes the option to unsubscribe from an email list at any time or to contact us to request to be excluded from our promotion or text messaging lists, if applicable. Where we rely on legitimate interests, you have the right to object.

If you have any questions about the lawful bases upon which we collect and use your personal data, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Additional information is provided below about lawful bases for processing of personal information.

· **Specific Consent:** Where you have provided specific consent to us using your personal information in a certain way, such as to send you emails, texts, direct mail, and/or telephone outreach. For example, you may have signed up for a newsletter or provided donations that we then process.

· **Performance of a contract** : Where we are entering into a contract with you or performing our obligations under it.

· **Legal obligation** : Where strictly necessary so that we can comply with a legal or regulatory obligation to which we are subject.

· **Legitimate interests** : Where it is reasonably necessary to achieve our or others’ legitimate interests as long as information uses and processing activities are “fair and lawful,” as required by the GDPR, and do not unduly impact your rights.

**Processing your Sensitive Personal Data** : We do not seek to collect or otherwise process your sensitive personal information (i.e. about race or ethnicity, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, etc.) except where the processing is required or permitted by applicable law; or we have obtained your prior explicit consent.

**Links to other websites  
**Our website may contain links to other websites run by other organizations. This Policy applies only to our website‚ so we encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit. We cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other websites, even if you access those using links from our website.

In addition, if you linked to our website from a third-party site, we cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of the owners and operators of that third-party site (except as described above) and recommend that you check the privacy Policy of that third-party site.

**Users 16 and under  
**We are concerned about protecting the privacy of children aged 16 or under. If you are aged 16 or under‚ please get your parent/guardian's permission beforehand whenever you provide us with personal information. 

Further, as noted in our [Terms of Use ](https://www.beforetheflood.com/terms/)you must be 13 years of age or older to use our website. If you believe that the website has information from or about anyone at or under 13 years of age, or from anyone at or under 16 years of age in GDPR-compliant countries, please notify us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

**Vulnerable circumstances  
**We are committed to protecting vulnerable supporters and volunteers and appreciate that additional care may be needed when we use their personal information. In recognition of this, we observe good practice guidelines in our interactions with individuals. If you require additional measures be put in place to protect your data please notify us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

**How can I get more information?  
**If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, your personal information, or data protection on this site, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) For your protection, we may only share and update the personal information associated with the specific email address that you use to send us your request, and we may need to verify your identity before doing so. We will comply with such requests in a reasonably timely manner. Please do not send sensitive personal information, passwords, banking details, or credit/debit card details via email.

**Changes to this policy  
**Please check this page regularly to ensure that you have no questions or concerns regarding the changes. If we make any significant changes, we will note those in the footer of all web pages, and we will provide the date of the last revision at the top of the Privacy Policy page.
